<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<description></description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Airbus Innovation Fun Day Challenge 2019</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;page-header-brief&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;line-sep&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0;&quot;&gt;Airbus Innovation Fun Day Challenge 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
	
	December
	7th,
	 2019
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Airbus Innovation Fun Day is a whole day event where six teams from across the nation compete head-to-head. The challenges (not surprisingly) are based around aviation and aerospace challenges. This year, I had the privelege to participate in this competition, which was coinciDON’Tally held between the completion of my final year project, and the start of my final exams. As consequence to this, the Taylor’s team (my team) had the utmost opportunity of being &lt;strong&gt;the most ill prepared team&lt;/strong&gt; for this competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition had three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The rocket drone challenge&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;A drone attached to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Water_rocket&quot;&gt;water rocket&lt;/a&gt; that has to achieve an altitude of 100 feet and land safely on a target no wider than an A4 sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The unknown challenge&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Essentially, the construction of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ornithopter&quot;&gt;flying ornithopter&lt;/a&gt; (think bird made of paper complete with flapping wings, it also flies) to be completed within 1.5 hours. This challenge was unbeknownst to us up until the actual challenge itself, and we were denied all access to digital technology, basically no interweb cheating.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The modular drone challenge&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;A drone that can, in no particular order: carry water bottles from point A to point B, be able to land on a body of water and take off again, fly through 40x40cm tunnels, endure a drop test from 6 meters, be capable of aggressive maneuvres to repeatedly cycle between two waypoints, and also be FPV capable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this challenge set, one would assume we’d have set aside 2 weeks in advance to come up with the required drone(s) to have the best chance of winning. One would also assume we’d have the luxury of a good supervisor on hand to aide in whatever uncertainty we may have. However, being the geniuses that we were (spoiler alert: we’re not), coupled with a tight schedule, and having need to adhere to laboratory operating hours, we had what could only be described as 10 hours of total prep time spread over 4 days. It was at this realization that we decided to only focus on the rocket drone challenge, and aim at performing that task well. The capability of the team to complete the unknown challenge was up for guesses. The last challenge we intended to gracefully withdraw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given these set of circumstances, what we had heading into the competition was a 250 quadrotor attached to a soda bottle with three ropes of electrical tape, and a spud gun to launch the whole contraption into the air, and a bicycle pump. Through sheer demotivation, we also brought no spare props or tools. There was one silver lining: the quadrotor in question was a very reliable drone with GPS and wifi telemetry capability, with a solid carbon frame and EMAX red bottom motors, linked to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rc.futaba.co.jp/english/propo/air/14sg.html&quot;&gt;Futaba T14SG transmitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reception&quot;&gt;Reception&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with utmost shame (no not really), that I admit we made it to the opening ceremony late. An hour late to be exact. It is also with utmost shame (lies), that I admit one of our team members overslept, and one of our team members (me) underestimate the time needed to make the drive to the venue. On top of this, have I mentioned that participation is done by teams of four to five, with at least one available supervisor at hand? Because we arrived as a team of three with no supervisor. To add to this, every other team had uniforms or shirts repsenting their respective universities, we were as casual as a cat on a lazy Sunday afternoon. Naturally, due to the presence of an unexpectedly small team coupled with being late, the crowd expectation for the Taylor’s team to perform was very low. To add on, many other teams had tools galore, heat guns, soldering irons, an abundance of props, prop tools, spare drone parts, &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; drones; think F1 team during a race, but for drones. Regardless of team presence, the competition had to go on, and go on it did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rocket-drone-challenge&quot;&gt;Rocket Drone Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complete this challenge, a few things needed to be accomplished. The first and most obvious is to launch the drone via water rocket to 100 feet. The second challenge was to prove that the drone was indeed at an altitude of 100 feet (wifi telemetry worked well for us). The third and final challenge was to then land the drone on a landing pad some 20 meters away from the launch site (yey GPS!). Considering that this was the challenge we prepared for, we performed it very well. I kid you not when I say the solution we came up with was to electrical tape (not even duct tape) our 250 drone to the top of a soda bottle (it was mountain dew), and fire it off the end of a spud gun pressurized to 700 kPa. Fortunately for us, we were the only team who completed each requirement successfully. One team had launched a bottle without a drone (?????), two other teams had drones (attached to bottle) come pummeling back to the planet, one team had what could be described a succesful launch and land without reaching 100 feet, and then there was us, flying flipping colours. Prior to our turn to perform launch, we had some of the organizing committee approach us and informing us that they were worried about our team. Post launch, I suppose I need not mention that they were just a little surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unknown-challenge&quot;&gt;Unknown Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unknwon challenge was to construct a flying ornithopter out of common materials like parchment paper, wooden skewers, popsicle sticks, cyanoacrylate glue, etc. If you don’t know what this is, I suggest watching a youtube &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gtn4PpZEB8I&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8o5H1Wo9o3w&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately for us, we’ve had an encounter with one of these contraptions before, though I can’t say the same for the other teams. Unfortunately, we couldn’t get ours to take off. Fortunately, the same can be said for every other team. The main obstacle we encountered as due to insufficiently tight tolerances in the drive shaft. This caused a lot of friction or binding up of the main motor, disallowing the wings from doing their thing. I do now know what proportion of the full score we attained for this challenge, but I’d like to think it was pretty high considering that we were the only team able to come up with a theoretically sound design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modular-drone-challenge&quot;&gt;Modular Drone Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the challenge that we did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; prepare for. However, knowing our progress throughout the previous challenges, we decided on the spot to use the same drone for the bottle rocket launch, and try to accomplish as much of this challenge that we’re able to. This includes landing on a body of water, the flight through the tunnels, repeated waypoint flights, drop testing, and catastrophically - carrying bottles of water from point A to point B. I say catastrophically because that was the first part of this challenge that we undertook, and flying a drone in stabilized mode carrying a hook to pick up a bottle with an eyelet the size of a bottle cap is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; easy. After 15 minutes of trying, the drone accomplished hooking one bottle, and proceeding to crash right after. It was also in this particular task that the drone crashed and exploded one of its props, and badly damaged the other 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that darned moment, our hearts were kind of slumped. We had no spare props, and were basically a sunken ship. Thankfully, the team at USM agreed to donate a set of spare props they had. Aside from using empty water bottles as floats to allow the drone to land on a body of water, there is not much excitement throughout this challenge other than what could be described as a lot of grit, determination, swearing, crashing, and just YOLO-ing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;closing&quot;&gt;Closing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was at the closing ceremony that our supervisor could finally make the one hour trip from work to where we were, and with hearts in our stomach that we were announced the winners of the competition. Quoting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/raymond-lim-94059a41/?originalSubdomain=my&quot;&gt;Raymond Lim&lt;/a&gt;: “You don’t need a whole team and many designs to win a competition, just three persons and a good design.” Honestly, this outcome is one which non of us expected: a surprise indeed, but a welcomed one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly special thanks goes to my two friends: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/aaron.chin.50&quot;&gt;Aaron Chin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/suann.minnie&quot;&gt;Low Su Ann&lt;/a&gt; for being just all round the best team mates I could ever ask for (as of December 2019, they also need jobs, so hire them please XD). Credit needs to also go to my supervisor, Dr Phang, for miraculously appearing during the prize giving ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/airbus-winning.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;From left to right: Raymond Lim, Phang Swee King, Low Su Ann, yours truly, Aaron Chin&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More pictures to be added when I have them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>/2019/12/07/airbus-competition.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/12/07/airbus-competition.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Obstacle Avoidance and Navigational Algorithm for UAVS</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;page-header-brief&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;line-sep&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0;&quot;&gt;Obstacle Avoidance and Navigational Algorithm for UAVS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
	
	December
	1st,
	 2019
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zM7Mar3_dCo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/zM7Mar3_dCo/maxresdefault.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;This is a video! Click the picture!&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All undergraduate engineering students have to complete a final year project as a prerequisite to graduating. This project ultimately culminates into the development of a thesis and/or conference paper and/or many other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My undergraduate degree was no different, and my project was titled “An Optimized Autonomous UAV with Obstacle Avoidance Capability”. I, for one, feel like the title itself only represented 50% of what I was doing correctly, and misrepresented another 50%. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-algorithm&quot;&gt;The Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/UAV_OAN.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;The UAV I used. It's a Tarot 650 platform with EMAX 4114 motors running 1555 carbon props. Controlling everything is a Pixhawk 4 flight controller hooked up to an Intel UP Squared companion computer. Everything is powered off a single 6S 5200 mAh lithium polymer battery.&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was working on for the better part of 8 months was a massively scalable obstacle avoidance and navigational (OAN) algorithm for mobile robots. It can work on any robot, but is optimized for UAVs. I didn’t optimize the actual hardware on the UAV itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the idea was that the algorithm had to be online, scalable, and lightweight. This meant that using any form of AI was out of the question, as such an implementation doesn’t grant me the scalability that I desired. It also had to be robust - reaching the target by any means necessary, and also smooth - allowing smooth UAV dynamics, such as those we have been accustomed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t get into the specifics here, should you require more information, don’t hesitate to email me, view the &lt;a href=&quot;google.com&quot;&gt;conference publishing&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jjshoots/TUAV-OAN.git&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt;. Effectively, the task was accomplished using what could be described as a mish mash of vector and potential fields, coupled with a path finding implementation to eliminate any form of local minima.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code in itself is implmented in ROS with C++, and my implementation is a tad clunky to say the least. A few improvements that I may work on in the future include changing the regular-schmegular A* algorithm to something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aaai.org/Papers/AAAI/2007/AAAI07-187.pdf&quot;&gt;Theta*&lt;/a&gt;, improving the stuck check conditional, converting the whole algorithm to work in 3D (the current implementation is only 2D with a fixed ground clearance), implementing SLAM and perhaps a few more code optimizations. But as a functioning OAN algorithm, &lt;em&gt;it works&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thoughts&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That aside, what I learnt the most about this project has nothing to do about the project itself. I learnt that the environment at which work is done has to first be very optimized for productivity (I see a lot of peers struggling with this, causing limited productivity). Also reinforced in belief is the fact that what I know is only the surface of what is out there. The latter of which is causing me to doubt my desires to pursue a PhD (if anyone has advice, do tell!). And to add a hint of cliche, I learnt the importance of friends and family. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this project is one that I’m proud of, but will always be just one project drowned among the many done before. It also won me an award, so there’s that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/EURECA.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Family. :)&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>/2019/12/01/oan.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/12/01/oan.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>So, I made a website!</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;page-header-brief&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;line-sep&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0;&quot;&gt;So, I made a website!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
	
	October
	28th,
	 2019
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; know there are thousands of HTML and CSS tutorials online right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You also &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; know that there are also online services that build websites based on a dead simple GUI right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I suppose the natural question after that is why it took me a total of 12 hours to get this dinky website up. If it weren’t already obvious, I am:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stubborn. I figured the most convenient way to learn about a totally new landscape was to make mistakes and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; google them afterwards. But we all know this didn’t really work did it? The language itself isn’t difficult, but having to figure out how each .md and .html and .css file interacted with each other over this unknown environment took me awhile. It still is my fault for burning daylight though. :P&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very easily distracted by details. I choose to spend time going through colour options for my site before I actually fix the framework of the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, that’s about it. For now, what follows is fixing all my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; tags to make styling with CSS easier. And then the follow up would be just simply adding more content! Both of which would unlikely be documented in here, but I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; kinda excited to see how this page evolves over time to be honest. In any case:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;succeed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;try_again&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>/2019/10/28/19-made-a-website.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/10/28/19-made-a-website.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
